2023-04-15 19:44:34 INFO - Scenario 'Font settings: Check of font style' start 2023-04-15 19:44:34 INFO - Setting application driver using the server on 'https://hub-cloud.browserstack.com/wd/hub' 2023-04-15 19:45:11 INFO - Application on platform 'ANDROID' is ready... 2023-04-15 19:45:11 INFO - Session id - b04e1ec1ab16a2a206148bea245f2d8e4a039d57 2023-04-15 19:45:11 INFO - Step 0 - Close tutorial screen 2023-04-15 19:45:11 INFO - Button 'btnCloseTutorial' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:45:13 INFO - Step 1 - Welcome screen is opened 2023-04-15 19:45:14 INFO - Step 2 - Close welcome screen 2023-04-15 19:45:14 INFO - Button 'btnFindLibrary' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:45:14 INFO - Step 3 - Add library screen is opened 2023-04-15 19:45:15 INFO - Step 4 - Add library "LYRASIS Reads" on Add library screen 2023-04-15 19:45:15 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:45:17 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Clearing 2023-04-15 19:45:17 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Typing 'LYRASIS Reads' 2023-04-15 19:45:20 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:45:20 INFO - Step 5 - Account "LYRASIS Reads" is present on Accounts screen 2023-04-15 19:45:20 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:45:22 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:45:23 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:45:24 INFO - Step 6 - Enter credentials for 'LYRASIS Reads' account 2023-04-15 19:45:25 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:45:25 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:45:26 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:45:27 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:45:28 INFO - Locking credential with barcode 01230000000003 2023-04-15 19:45:28 INFO - There are books on the account: 2023-04-15 19:45:29 INFO - bookName: The Montessori Baby Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-04-15 19:45:29 INFO - bookName: Goliath Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-04-15 19:45:29 INFO - bookName: The Black Kids Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-04-15 19:45:29 INFO - bookName: Children of Virtue and Vengeance Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-04-15 19:45:29 INFO - Count of books on the account after opening account: 4 2023-04-15 19:45:29 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Clearing 2023-04-15 19:45:29 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Typing '01230000000003' 2023-04-15 19:45:31 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Clearing 2023-04-15 19:45:31 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Typing '********' 2023-04-15 19:45:33 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:45:39 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:45:39 INFO - Step 7 - Login is performed successfully 2023-04-15 19:46:01 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:46:01 INFO - Step 8 - Open Catalog 2023-04-15 19:46:01 INFO - Button 'tabCatalog' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:46:21 INFO - Step 9 - Open search modal 2023-04-15 19:46:42 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:46:43 INFO - Step 10 - Search 'available' book of distributor 'Axis 360' and bookType 'EBOOK' from "LYRASIS Reads" and save as 'bookNameInfo' 2023-04-15 19:46:43 INFO - Count of attempts to get random book name without bad symbols-1 2023-04-15 19:46:43 INFO - randomBookName: Quicksand 2023-04-15 19:46:43 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-04-15 19:46:44 INFO - Text Field 'Search value input' :: Sending keys 'Quicksand' 2023-04-15 19:46:46 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-04-15 19:46:48 INFO - Step 11 - Click GET action button on EBOOK book with 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-04-15 19:46:49 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:46:49 INFO - Button 'actionButton' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:46:57 INFO - Step 12 - Open EBOOK book with READ action button and 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-04-15 19:46:57 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:46:57 INFO - Label 'lblBookName' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:46:58 INFO - Step 13 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-04-15 19:46:59 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:46:59 INFO - Step 14 - Scroll page forward from 7 to 9 times 2023-04-15 19:46:59 INFO - Scrolling 7 times on reader epub screen 2023-04-15 19:47:19 INFO - Step 15 - Open font settings 2023-04-15 19:47:20 INFO - Button 'btnFontSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:47:21 INFO - Step 16 - Change font style to FONT_SERIF 2023-04-15 19:47:21 INFO - Button 'setFontSerif' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:47:22 INFO - Step 17 - Book text displays in FONT_SERIF font 2023-04-15 19:47:22 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:47:22 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-04-15 19:47:23 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:47:23 INFO -

Week 1 of Trial: Monday

1.

The first time I saw the inside of a courtroom, I was disappointed. We visited one for a class trip, and sure, I had already figured out that Swedish judges aren’t stooping old men in curly wigs and long robes, and that the defendant wouldn’t be a madman in an orange suit, in handcuffs, frothing at the mouth, but still. The place looked like something between a medical clinic and a conference center. We rode there on a rented bus that smelled like bubblegum and sweaty feet. The defendant had dandruff and pleated pants and was allegedly guilty of tax evasion. Aside from our class (and Christer, of course), there were only four other people there to listen, but so few seats that Christer had to get an extra chair from the hallway outside so he had somewhere to sit.

Today it’s different. We’re in the largest courtroom in Sweden. The judges sit on chairs of dark mahogany with high velvet backs. The middle chair’s back is taller than the others’. That’s where the head judge sits. He is called the “chairman.” On the table in front of him is a gavel with a leather handle. Slim microphones stick up before each seat like bent drinking straws. The paneling on the wall looks like oak, like it’s several hundred years old, old in a good way. There is a dark red carpet on the floor between the seats.

Audiences are not my thing. I’ve never wanted to be St. Lucia or take part in talent shows. But it’s packed in here. And everyone is here because of me; I’m the attraction.

Next to me are my attorneys from Sander & Laestadius. I know Sander & Laestadius sounds like an antique shop where two sweaty gay men in silk robes and monocles shuffle around with kerosene lamps dusting off moldy books and taxidermied animals, but it’s Sweden’s best criminal law firm. Ordinary criminals have a single weary public defender; my public defender is flanked by a whole crew of excited wannabe-suits. They work into the wee hours at a super-fancy office near Skeppsbron, have at least two cell phones each, and all of them except Sander himself think that they’re part of an American TV show where you eat Chinese food from take-out cartons in an I’m-so-busy-and-important sort of way. None of all the twenty-two people working at Sander & Laestadius is actually named Laestadius. Laestadius died, I assume of a heart attack, in an I’m-so-busy-and-important sort of way.

Three of my attorneys are here today: Peder Sander, the celebrity, and two of his colleagues. The younger one is a chick with an ugly haircut and a piercing in her nose but no ring in it. Presumably Sander won’t allow her to wear a nose ring (“Remove that junk immediately”). I call her Ferdinand. Ferdinand is the type of person who thinks “conservative” is a curse word and nuclear power is lethal. She wears hideous glasses because she thinks it proves that she’s got the patriarchy all figured out, and she hates me because, in her opinion, capitalism is all my fault. The first few times we met, she treated me like I was a crazy fashion blogger with a hand grenade on an airplane. “Of course, of course!” she said, not daring to look at me. “Of course, of course! Don’t worry, we’re here to help you.” As if I would threaten to blow everyone to bits unless I received my biodynamic tomato juice with no ice.

The other helper attorney is a guy around forty with a doughy belly, a pancake-shaped face, and a smile that says, “I’ve got movies at home that I keep in alphabetical order in a locked cabinet.” Pancake has a buzz cut. Dad likes to say that you can’t trust a person with no hairstyle. But I’m sure Dad didn’t come up with that on his own; he probably stole it from a movie. My dad really likes to deliver one-liners.

The first time I met Pancake, he rested his eyes just below my collarbone, forced his thick tongue back in his mouth, and rasped in delight, “Little girl, what are we going to do? You look much older than seventeen.” He probably would have started panting if Sander hadn’t been there. Or drooling, maybe. Let the saliva drip from his mouth and stain his too-tight suit vest. I couldn’t bring myself to point out that I was eighteen.

Today, Pancake is sitting on my left. He brought a briefcase and a wheeled case stuffed full of folders and documents. He has emptied the case and now the folders are on the table in front of him. The only things he left in the case were a book (Make Your Case—Winning Is the Only Option) and a toothbrush sticking up from one of the little inside pockets. Sitting behind me, in the first row of the audience, are Mom and Dad.

When I was on that class trip two years and an eternity ago, our class had been given a run-through beforehand, so we would “appreciate the importance” and “be able to follow along.” I doubt it helped. But we “behaved,” as Christer said when we left. He had been afraid we wouldn’t be able to keep from giggling and taking out our cell phones. That we were planning to sit there playing games and sleeping with our chins resting on our collars like bored members of Parliament.

I remember Christer’s grave voice as he explained (“Hey now, listen up!”) that a trial is nothing to be flippant about; people’s lives are at stake. You are innocent until the courts have ruled that you are guilty. That’s what he said, several times. Samir leaned back as Christer spoke, balancing on his chair and nodding like he always did, the way that made all the teachers love him. Nods that said I understand completely, we are on the exact same wavelength and I have nothing to add because everything you say is so smart.

You are innocent until the courts have ruled that you are guilty. What kind of weird statement is that? Either you’re innocent all along, or else you did it, right from the start. Shouldn’t the court try to figure out which it is, rather than decide what happened? The police and the prosecutor and the judges weren’t there and don’t know exactly who did what, so how can the court make it up after the fact?

I recall that I pointed this out to Christer. That courts are wrong all the time. Rapists are always going free. There’s not even any point in reporting a sexual assault, because even if you were force-fucked by half a refugee camp and you get an entire case’s worth of bottles shoved up between your legs, they never believe the girl. And that doesn’t mean that it didn’t happen, and that the rapist didn’t do what he did.

“It’s not that simple,” said Christer.

What a typical teacher answer: “That’s an excellent question…” “I hear what you’re saying…” “It’s not black and white…” “It’s not that simple…” Those kinds of answers all mean the same thing: They have no idea what they’re talking about.

But fine. If it’s difficult to know what’s true and who’s lying, if you can’t be sure, then what do you do?

I read somewhere that “the truth is whatever we choose to believe.” Which sounds even more insane, if that’s even possible. Like someone can just decide what’s true and what’s false? Things can be both true and made up, depending on whom you ask? And if someone we trust says something, well, then we can just decide that it’s so, we can “choose that it’s true.” How can anyone even come up with something so idiotic? If a person were to say to me that he “chooses to believe me,” I would know right away that he’s actually convinced that I’m lying but he’s going to pretend otherwise.

My attorney Sander seems mostly indifferent to all of this. All he says is, “I’m on your side,” while his face looks like a thumbnail. Sander is not, like, the excitable type. Everything about him is relaxed and under control. No outbursts. No feelings. No roaring laughter. Probably he didn’t even cry at birth.

Sander is the opposite of my dad. Dad is far from the “cool guy” (his words) he wishes he were. He grinds his teeth in his sleep and jumps to his feet when he watches the national team play soccer. My dad gets mad, furious, at pedantic city employees, the neighbor who parked illegally for the fourth time in one week, incomprehensible electric bills, and telemarketers. Computers, immigration officers, Grandpa, the grill, mosquitoes, unshoveled sidewalks, Germans in the ski-lift line, and French waiters. Everything riles him up, makes him yell and shout, slam doors and tell people to go to hell. With Sander, however, the clearest sign that he’s pissed off, almost insane with anger, is that he gets a wrinkle on his forehead and makes a clicking sound with his tongue. And then all his colleagues become terrified and start stammering and looking for documents and books and other things they think will put him in a better mood. Kind of like how Mom handles Dad on the rare occasions he’s not annoyed but is acting perfectly calm and quiet.

Sander has never gotten mad at me. He’s never been upset over something I told him or grumpy about something I didn’t say or when I was lying and he knew it.

“I’m on your side, Maja.” Sometimes he sounds more tired than usual, but that’s it. “The truth” is not something we talk about.

For the most part, I think it’s nice that Sander only cares about what the police and the prosecutor have proven. I don’t have to worry about whether he is planning to do a good job or is just pretending he’s going to. It’s like he’s taken all the dead and all the guilt and all the agony and turned it into numbers, and if the equations don’t add up, then he wins.

Maybe that’s how it should be done. One plus one cannot equal three. Next question, please.

But that’s of no help to me, of course. Because either something happened or it didn’t. It is what it is. All the rest is just beating around the bush, the kind of thing that philosophers do, as well as (apparently) a lawyer here and there. Constructs. “It’s not that simple…”

But Christer, I remember how insistent he was before that court visit, he really did everything he could to get us to listen. You are innocent until the court has ruled that you are guilty. He wrote it on the board: a fundamental principle of law. (Samir nodded again.) Christer asked us to take notes. Copy it down. (Samir copied it down. Even though he hardly needed to.)

Christer loved anything short enough to memorize that could be turned into a test question. The correct answer was worth two points on the exam we took two weeks later. Why not one point? Because Christer thought there were gray areas in memorized responses, that you could be almost right. No, one plus one cannot equal three, but I’ll give you partial credit because you answered in the form of a number.

That visit to the court with Christer happened more than two years ago. Sebastian wasn’t there; he wasn’t in our class until our final year, the year he had to repeat. I liked school back then, pretty much, with my classmates and the teachers we’d had in different renditions since our elementary days: the chemistry teacher, Jonas, who spoke too quietly, never remembered anyone’s name, and waited for the bus wearing his backpack on his front. The French teacher, Mari-Louise, with her glasses and dandelion hair, who was always sucking so hard on a tiny sliver of a black lozenge that her mouth became as small and puckered as a wild strawberry. Shorthaired Gym Friggan, who looked like a freshly polished wooden deck: indistinct gender, a whistle around the neck, and broad, shiny, clean-shaven calves, always surrounded by the odor of gym socks and someone else’s sweat. Absentminded Malin, our bottle-blonde math teacher: dissatisfied and constantly late, off sick on average two days a week, and with a photo of herself twenty years slimmer, wearing a string bikini in her profile picture on Facebook.

And Christer Svensson. Dedicated, in a let’s-meet-at-Mariatorget-and-take-a-stand sort of way; ordinary, in a pork-chops-and-mashed-potatoes-and-gravy sort of way. He thought rock concerts could save the world from war, famine, and disease, and he always spoke in that overenthusiastic teacher voice that no one should ever use for anything but getting a dog to wag its tail.

Every day, Christer brought a thermos of home-brewed coffee to school, with so much sugar and milk in it that it looked like liquid foundation. He would pour his coffee into his mug (“World’s Best Dad”) and bring the mug to class and refill it during our lessons. Christer loved routines, same thing every day, favorite song on repeat. He had probably eaten the same thing for breakfast ever since he was fourteen: some sort of cross-country skier thing, like oatmeal with lingonberries and whole milk (“Breakfast is the most important meal of the day!”), I’m sure he drank beer and a shot on the side every time he met up with his friends (“buddies”), ate tacos with his family every Friday, and went to the neighborhood pizzeria (one with crayons and paper for the kids) and split a bottle of the house red with “the wife” when he wanted to celebrate something major and important. Christer had no imagination, he went on charter trips, he would never cook with coriander or fry things in anything but butter.

We first had Christer as a teacher in our first year of upper secondary. He complained at least once a week about how the weather had gotten so strange (“There aren’t seasons anymore”), and every autumn he complained that Christmas decorations went up earlier and earlier (“Soon there will probably be a Christmas tree on Skeppsbron even before the summer ferries stop running.”)

He complained about the evening tabloids (“Why would anyone read that shit?”) and Dancing with the Stars, Eurovision, and Paradise Hotel (“Why would anyone watch that shit?”). Most of all he hated our cell phones (“Are you cows? With those chat apps dinging and jingling constantly, you might as well be wearing bells around your necks…Why do you bother with that shit?”). Every time he complained, he looked pleased, he thought he was youthful and “cool” (not just a Dad word), and that it was proof of how close he was with his students that he could use words like “shit” in front of us.

Christer stuck a pouch of snus under his upper lip after each cup of coffee and collected the used ones in a napkin before throwing them in the trash. Christer liked things neat and tidy, even his garbage.

And afterward, when the tax evader’s trial was over and we went back to the school, he was pleased. He thought we had handled ourselves “well.” Christer was always “pleased” or “concerned,” never overjoyed or totally pissed off. Christer always wanted to give at least partial credit on memorized answers.

Christer was lying down when he died. With his arms around his head and his knees tucked up, more or less how my little sister Lina looks when she’s sleeping most deeply. He bled to death before the ambulance arrived, and I wonder if his wife and his kids feel like things aren’t so simple in reality and that I am innocent because no court has yet determined that I am guilty.

2023-04-15 19:47:23 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:47:24 INFO - Step 18 - Restart app 2023-04-15 19:47:48 INFO - Step 19 - Open Books 2023-04-15 19:47:48 INFO - Button 'tabBooks' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:47:49 INFO - Step 20 - Open EBOOK book with READ action button and 'bookInfo' bookInfo on books screen 2023-04-15 19:47:49 INFO - Label 'lblBookName' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:47:51 INFO - Step 21 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-04-15 19:47:52 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:47:52 INFO - Step 22 - Book text displays in FONT_SERIF font 2023-04-15 19:47:52 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:47:53 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:47:54 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:47:54 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:47:54 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-04-15 19:47:55 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:47:55 INFO -

Week 1 of Trial: Monday

1.

The first time I saw the inside of a courtroom, I was disappointed. We visited one for a class trip, and sure, I had already figured out that Swedish judges aren’t stooping old men in curly wigs and long robes, and that the defendant wouldn’t be a madman in an orange suit, in handcuffs, frothing at the mouth, but still. The place looked like something between a medical clinic and a conference center. We rode there on a rented bus that smelled like bubblegum and sweaty feet. The defendant had dandruff and pleated pants and was allegedly guilty of tax evasion. Aside from our class (and Christer, of course), there were only four other people there to listen, but so few seats that Christer had to get an extra chair from the hallway outside so he had somewhere to sit.

Today it’s different. We’re in the largest courtroom in Sweden. The judges sit on chairs of dark mahogany with high velvet backs. The middle chair’s back is taller than the others’. That’s where the head judge sits. He is called the “chairman.” On the table in front of him is a gavel with a leather handle. Slim microphones stick up before each seat like bent drinking straws. The paneling on the wall looks like oak, like it’s several hundred years old, old in a good way. There is a dark red carpet on the floor between the seats.

Audiences are not my thing. I’ve never wanted to be St. Lucia or take part in talent shows. But it’s packed in here. And everyone is here because of me; I’m the attraction.

Next to me are my attorneys from Sander & Laestadius. I know Sander & Laestadius sounds like an antique shop where two sweaty gay men in silk robes and monocles shuffle around with kerosene lamps dusting off moldy books and taxidermied animals, but it’s Sweden’s best criminal law firm. Ordinary criminals have a single weary public defender; my public defender is flanked by a whole crew of excited wannabe-suits. They work into the wee hours at a super-fancy office near Skeppsbron, have at least two cell phones each, and all of them except Sander himself think that they’re part of an American TV show where you eat Chinese food from take-out cartons in an I’m-so-busy-and-important sort of way. None of all the twenty-two people working at Sander & Laestadius is actually named Laestadius. Laestadius died, I assume of a heart attack, in an I’m-so-busy-and-important sort of way.

Three of my attorneys are here today: Peder Sander, the celebrity, and two of his colleagues. The younger one is a chick with an ugly haircut and a piercing in her nose but no ring in it. Presumably Sander won’t allow her to wear a nose ring (“Remove that junk immediately”). I call her Ferdinand. Ferdinand is the type of person who thinks “conservative” is a curse word and nuclear power is lethal. She wears hideous glasses because she thinks it proves that she’s got the patriarchy all figured out, and she hates me because, in her opinion, capitalism is all my fault. The first few times we met, she treated me like I was a crazy fashion blogger with a hand grenade on an airplane. “Of course, of course!” she said, not daring to look at me. “Of course, of course! Don’t worry, we’re here to help you.” As if I would threaten to blow everyone to bits unless I received my biodynamic tomato juice with no ice.

The other helper attorney is a guy around forty with a doughy belly, a pancake-shaped face, and a smile that says, “I’ve got movies at home that I keep in alphabetical order in a locked cabinet.” Pancake has a buzz cut. Dad likes to say that you can’t trust a person with no hairstyle. But I’m sure Dad didn’t come up with that on his own; he probably stole it from a movie. My dad really likes to deliver one-liners.

The first time I met Pancake, he rested his eyes just below my collarbone, forced his thick tongue back in his mouth, and rasped in delight, “Little girl, what are we going to do? You look much older than seventeen.” He probably would have started panting if Sander hadn’t been there. Or drooling, maybe. Let the saliva drip from his mouth and stain his too-tight suit vest. I couldn’t bring myself to point out that I was eighteen.

Today, Pancake is sitting on my left. He brought a briefcase and a wheeled case stuffed full of folders and documents. He has emptied the case and now the folders are on the table in front of him. The only things he left in the case were a book (Make Your Case—Winning Is the Only Option) and a toothbrush sticking up from one of the little inside pockets. Sitting behind me, in the first row of the audience, are Mom and Dad.

When I was on that class trip two years and an eternity ago, our class had been given a run-through beforehand, so we would “appreciate the importance” and “be able to follow along.” I doubt it helped. But we “behaved,” as Christer said when we left. He had been afraid we wouldn’t be able to keep from giggling and taking out our cell phones. That we were planning to sit there playing games and sleeping with our chins resting on our collars like bored members of Parliament.

I remember Christer’s grave voice as he explained (“Hey now, listen up!”) that a trial is nothing to be flippant about; people’s lives are at stake. You are innocent until the courts have ruled that you are guilty. That’s what he said, several times. Samir leaned back as Christer spoke, balancing on his chair and nodding like he always did, the way that made all the teachers love him. Nods that said I understand completely, we are on the exact same wavelength and I have nothing to add because everything you say is so smart.

You are innocent until the courts have ruled that you are guilty. What kind of weird statement is that? Either you’re innocent all along, or else you did it, right from the start. Shouldn’t the court try to figure out which it is, rather than decide what happened? The police and the prosecutor and the judges weren’t there and don’t know exactly who did what, so how can the court make it up after the fact?

I recall that I pointed this out to Christer. That courts are wrong all the time. Rapists are always going free. There’s not even any point in reporting a sexual assault, because even if you were force-fucked by half a refugee camp and you get an entire case’s worth of bottles shoved up between your legs, they never believe the girl. And that doesn’t mean that it didn’t happen, and that the rapist didn’t do what he did.

“It’s not that simple,” said Christer.

What a typical teacher answer: “That’s an excellent question…” “I hear what you’re saying…” “It’s not black and white…” “It’s not that simple…” Those kinds of answers all mean the same thing: They have no idea what they’re talking about.

But fine. If it’s difficult to know what’s true and who’s lying, if you can’t be sure, then what do you do?

I read somewhere that “the truth is whatever we choose to believe.” Which sounds even more insane, if that’s even possible. Like someone can just decide what’s true and what’s false? Things can be both true and made up, depending on whom you ask? And if someone we trust says something, well, then we can just decide that it’s so, we can “choose that it’s true.” How can anyone even come up with something so idiotic? If a person were to say to me that he “chooses to believe me,” I would know right away that he’s actually convinced that I’m lying but he’s going to pretend otherwise.

My attorney Sander seems mostly indifferent to all of this. All he says is, “I’m on your side,” while his face looks like a thumbnail. Sander is not, like, the excitable type. Everything about him is relaxed and under control. No outbursts. No feelings. No roaring laughter. Probably he didn’t even cry at birth.

Sander is the opposite of my dad. Dad is far from the “cool guy” (his words) he wishes he were. He grinds his teeth in his sleep and jumps to his feet when he watches the national team play soccer. My dad gets mad, furious, at pedantic city employees, the neighbor who parked illegally for the fourth time in one week, incomprehensible electric bills, and telemarketers. Computers, immigration officers, Grandpa, the grill, mosquitoes, unshoveled sidewalks, Germans in the ski-lift line, and French waiters. Everything riles him up, makes him yell and shout, slam doors and tell people to go to hell. With Sander, however, the clearest sign that he’s pissed off, almost insane with anger, is that he gets a wrinkle on his forehead and makes a clicking sound with his tongue. And then all his colleagues become terrified and start stammering and looking for documents and books and other things they think will put him in a better mood. Kind of like how Mom handles Dad on the rare occasions he’s not annoyed but is acting perfectly calm and quiet.

Sander has never gotten mad at me. He’s never been upset over something I told him or grumpy about something I didn’t say or when I was lying and he knew it.

“I’m on your side, Maja.” Sometimes he sounds more tired than usual, but that’s it. “The truth” is not something we talk about.

For the most part, I think it’s nice that Sander only cares about what the police and the prosecutor have proven. I don’t have to worry about whether he is planning to do a good job or is just pretending he’s going to. It’s like he’s taken all the dead and all the guilt and all the agony and turned it into numbers, and if the equations don’t add up, then he wins.

Maybe that’s how it should be done. One plus one cannot equal three. Next question, please.

But that’s of no help to me, of course. Because either something happened or it didn’t. It is what it is. All the rest is just beating around the bush, the kind of thing that philosophers do, as well as (apparently) a lawyer here and there. Constructs. “It’s not that simple…”

But Christer, I remember how insistent he was before that court visit, he really did everything he could to get us to listen. You are innocent until the court has ruled that you are guilty. He wrote it on the board: a fundamental principle of law. (Samir nodded again.) Christer asked us to take notes. Copy it down. (Samir copied it down. Even though he hardly needed to.)

Christer loved anything short enough to memorize that could be turned into a test question. The correct answer was worth two points on the exam we took two weeks later. Why not one point? Because Christer thought there were gray areas in memorized responses, that you could be almost right. No, one plus one cannot equal three, but I’ll give you partial credit because you answered in the form of a number.

That visit to the court with Christer happened more than two years ago. Sebastian wasn’t there; he wasn’t in our class until our final year, the year he had to repeat. I liked school back then, pretty much, with my classmates and the teachers we’d had in different renditions since our elementary days: the chemistry teacher, Jonas, who spoke too quietly, never remembered anyone’s name, and waited for the bus wearing his backpack on his front. The French teacher, Mari-Louise, with her glasses and dandelion hair, who was always sucking so hard on a tiny sliver of a black lozenge that her mouth became as small and puckered as a wild strawberry. Shorthaired Gym Friggan, who looked like a freshly polished wooden deck: indistinct gender, a whistle around the neck, and broad, shiny, clean-shaven calves, always surrounded by the odor of gym socks and someone else’s sweat. Absentminded Malin, our bottle-blonde math teacher: dissatisfied and constantly late, off sick on average two days a week, and with a photo of herself twenty years slimmer, wearing a string bikini in her profile picture on Facebook.

And Christer Svensson. Dedicated, in a let’s-meet-at-Mariatorget-and-take-a-stand sort of way; ordinary, in a pork-chops-and-mashed-potatoes-and-gravy sort of way. He thought rock concerts could save the world from war, famine, and disease, and he always spoke in that overenthusiastic teacher voice that no one should ever use for anything but getting a dog to wag its tail.

Every day, Christer brought a thermos of home-brewed coffee to school, with so much sugar and milk in it that it looked like liquid foundation. He would pour his coffee into his mug (“World’s Best Dad”) and bring the mug to class and refill it during our lessons. Christer loved routines, same thing every day, favorite song on repeat. He had probably eaten the same thing for breakfast ever since he was fourteen: some sort of cross-country skier thing, like oatmeal with lingonberries and whole milk (“Breakfast is the most important meal of the day!”), I’m sure he drank beer and a shot on the side every time he met up with his friends (“buddies”), ate tacos with his family every Friday, and went to the neighborhood pizzeria (one with crayons and paper for the kids) and split a bottle of the house red with “the wife” when he wanted to celebrate something major and important. Christer had no imagination, he went on charter trips, he would never cook with coriander or fry things in anything but butter.

We first had Christer as a teacher in our first year of upper secondary. He complained at least once a week about how the weather had gotten so strange (“There aren’t seasons anymore”), and every autumn he complained that Christmas decorations went up earlier and earlier (“Soon there will probably be a Christmas tree on Skeppsbron even before the summer ferries stop running.”)

He complained about the evening tabloids (“Why would anyone read that shit?”) and Dancing with the Stars, Eurovision, and Paradise Hotel (“Why would anyone watch that shit?”). Most of all he hated our cell phones (“Are you cows? With those chat apps dinging and jingling constantly, you might as well be wearing bells around your necks…Why do you bother with that shit?”). Every time he complained, he looked pleased, he thought he was youthful and “cool” (not just a Dad word), and that it was proof of how close he was with his students that he could use words like “shit” in front of us.

Christer stuck a pouch of snus under his upper lip after each cup of coffee and collected the used ones in a napkin before throwing them in the trash. Christer liked things neat and tidy, even his garbage.

And afterward, when the tax evader’s trial was over and we went back to the school, he was pleased. He thought we had handled ourselves “well.” Christer was always “pleased” or “concerned,” never overjoyed or totally pissed off. Christer always wanted to give at least partial credit on memorized answers.

Christer was lying down when he died. With his arms around his head and his knees tucked up, more or less how my little sister Lina looks when she’s sleeping most deeply. He bled to death before the ambulance arrived, and I wonder if his wife and his kids feel like things aren’t so simple in reality and that I am innocent because no court has yet determined that I am guilty.

2023-04-15 19:47:55 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:47:56 INFO - Step 23 - Return to previous screen from epub 2023-04-15 19:47:57 INFO - Button 'btnBack' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:47:57 INFO - Step 24 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-04-15 19:47:58 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:47:59 INFO - Step 25 - Book text displays in FONT_SERIF font 2023-04-15 19:47:59 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:47:59 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-04-15 19:48:00 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:48:01 INFO -

Week 1 of Trial: Monday

1.

The first time I saw the inside of a courtroom, I was disappointed. We visited one for a class trip, and sure, I had already figured out that Swedish judges aren’t stooping old men in curly wigs and long robes, and that the defendant wouldn’t be a madman in an orange suit, in handcuffs, frothing at the mouth, but still. The place looked like something between a medical clinic and a conference center. We rode there on a rented bus that smelled like bubblegum and sweaty feet. The defendant had dandruff and pleated pants and was allegedly guilty of tax evasion. Aside from our class (and Christer, of course), there were only four other people there to listen, but so few seats that Christer had to get an extra chair from the hallway outside so he had somewhere to sit.

Today it’s different. We’re in the largest courtroom in Sweden. The judges sit on chairs of dark mahogany with high velvet backs. The middle chair’s back is taller than the others’. That’s where the head judge sits. He is called the “chairman.” On the table in front of him is a gavel with a leather handle. Slim microphones stick up before each seat like bent drinking straws. The paneling on the wall looks like oak, like it’s several hundred years old, old in a good way. There is a dark red carpet on the floor between the seats.

Audiences are not my thing. I’ve never wanted to be St. Lucia or take part in talent shows. But it’s packed in here. And everyone is here because of me; I’m the attraction.

Next to me are my attorneys from Sander & Laestadius. I know Sander & Laestadius sounds like an antique shop where two sweaty gay men in silk robes and monocles shuffle around with kerosene lamps dusting off moldy books and taxidermied animals, but it’s Sweden’s best criminal law firm. Ordinary criminals have a single weary public defender; my public defender is flanked by a whole crew of excited wannabe-suits. They work into the wee hours at a super-fancy office near Skeppsbron, have at least two cell phones each, and all of them except Sander himself think that they’re part of an American TV show where you eat Chinese food from take-out cartons in an I’m-so-busy-and-important sort of way. None of all the twenty-two people working at Sander & Laestadius is actually named Laestadius. Laestadius died, I assume of a heart attack, in an I’m-so-busy-and-important sort of way.

Three of my attorneys are here today: Peder Sander, the celebrity, and two of his colleagues. The younger one is a chick with an ugly haircut and a piercing in her nose but no ring in it. Presumably Sander won’t allow her to wear a nose ring (“Remove that junk immediately”). I call her Ferdinand. Ferdinand is the type of person who thinks “conservative” is a curse word and nuclear power is lethal. She wears hideous glasses because she thinks it proves that she’s got the patriarchy all figured out, and she hates me because, in her opinion, capitalism is all my fault. The first few times we met, she treated me like I was a crazy fashion blogger with a hand grenade on an airplane. “Of course, of course!” she said, not daring to look at me. “Of course, of course! Don’t worry, we’re here to help you.” As if I would threaten to blow everyone to bits unless I received my biodynamic tomato juice with no ice.

The other helper attorney is a guy around forty with a doughy belly, a pancake-shaped face, and a smile that says, “I’ve got movies at home that I keep in alphabetical order in a locked cabinet.” Pancake has a buzz cut. Dad likes to say that you can’t trust a person with no hairstyle. But I’m sure Dad didn’t come up with that on his own; he probably stole it from a movie. My dad really likes to deliver one-liners.

The first time I met Pancake, he rested his eyes just below my collarbone, forced his thick tongue back in his mouth, and rasped in delight, “Little girl, what are we going to do? You look much older than seventeen.” He probably would have started panting if Sander hadn’t been there. Or drooling, maybe. Let the saliva drip from his mouth and stain his too-tight suit vest. I couldn’t bring myself to point out that I was eighteen.

Today, Pancake is sitting on my left. He brought a briefcase and a wheeled case stuffed full of folders and documents. He has emptied the case and now the folders are on the table in front of him. The only things he left in the case were a book (Make Your Case—Winning Is the Only Option) and a toothbrush sticking up from one of the little inside pockets. Sitting behind me, in the first row of the audience, are Mom and Dad.

When I was on that class trip two years and an eternity ago, our class had been given a run-through beforehand, so we would “appreciate the importance” and “be able to follow along.” I doubt it helped. But we “behaved,” as Christer said when we left. He had been afraid we wouldn’t be able to keep from giggling and taking out our cell phones. That we were planning to sit there playing games and sleeping with our chins resting on our collars like bored members of Parliament.

I remember Christer’s grave voice as he explained (“Hey now, listen up!”) that a trial is nothing to be flippant about; people’s lives are at stake. You are innocent until the courts have ruled that you are guilty. That’s what he said, several times. Samir leaned back as Christer spoke, balancing on his chair and nodding like he always did, the way that made all the teachers love him. Nods that said I understand completely, we are on the exact same wavelength and I have nothing to add because everything you say is so smart.

You are innocent until the courts have ruled that you are guilty. What kind of weird statement is that? Either you’re innocent all along, or else you did it, right from the start. Shouldn’t the court try to figure out which it is, rather than decide what happened? The police and the prosecutor and the judges weren’t there and don’t know exactly who did what, so how can the court make it up after the fact?

I recall that I pointed this out to Christer. That courts are wrong all the time. Rapists are always going free. There’s not even any point in reporting a sexual assault, because even if you were force-fucked by half a refugee camp and you get an entire case’s worth of bottles shoved up between your legs, they never believe the girl. And that doesn’t mean that it didn’t happen, and that the rapist didn’t do what he did.

“It’s not that simple,” said Christer.

What a typical teacher answer: “That’s an excellent question…” “I hear what you’re saying…” “It’s not black and white…” “It’s not that simple…” Those kinds of answers all mean the same thing: They have no idea what they’re talking about.

But fine. If it’s difficult to know what’s true and who’s lying, if you can’t be sure, then what do you do?

I read somewhere that “the truth is whatever we choose to believe.” Which sounds even more insane, if that’s even possible. Like someone can just decide what’s true and what’s false? Things can be both true and made up, depending on whom you ask? And if someone we trust says something, well, then we can just decide that it’s so, we can “choose that it’s true.” How can anyone even come up with something so idiotic? If a person were to say to me that he “chooses to believe me,” I would know right away that he’s actually convinced that I’m lying but he’s going to pretend otherwise.

My attorney Sander seems mostly indifferent to all of this. All he says is, “I’m on your side,” while his face looks like a thumbnail. Sander is not, like, the excitable type. Everything about him is relaxed and under control. No outbursts. No feelings. No roaring laughter. Probably he didn’t even cry at birth.

Sander is the opposite of my dad. Dad is far from the “cool guy” (his words) he wishes he were. He grinds his teeth in his sleep and jumps to his feet when he watches the national team play soccer. My dad gets mad, furious, at pedantic city employees, the neighbor who parked illegally for the fourth time in one week, incomprehensible electric bills, and telemarketers. Computers, immigration officers, Grandpa, the grill, mosquitoes, unshoveled sidewalks, Germans in the ski-lift line, and French waiters. Everything riles him up, makes him yell and shout, slam doors and tell people to go to hell. With Sander, however, the clearest sign that he’s pissed off, almost insane with anger, is that he gets a wrinkle on his forehead and makes a clicking sound with his tongue. And then all his colleagues become terrified and start stammering and looking for documents and books and other things they think will put him in a better mood. Kind of like how Mom handles Dad on the rare occasions he’s not annoyed but is acting perfectly calm and quiet.

Sander has never gotten mad at me. He’s never been upset over something I told him or grumpy about something I didn’t say or when I was lying and he knew it.

“I’m on your side, Maja.” Sometimes he sounds more tired than usual, but that’s it. “The truth” is not something we talk about.

For the most part, I think it’s nice that Sander only cares about what the police and the prosecutor have proven. I don’t have to worry about whether he is planning to do a good job or is just pretending he’s going to. It’s like he’s taken all the dead and all the guilt and all the agony and turned it into numbers, and if the equations don’t add up, then he wins.

Maybe that’s how it should be done. One plus one cannot equal three. Next question, please.

But that’s of no help to me, of course. Because either something happened or it didn’t. It is what it is. All the rest is just beating around the bush, the kind of thing that philosophers do, as well as (apparently) a lawyer here and there. Constructs. “It’s not that simple…”

But Christer, I remember how insistent he was before that court visit, he really did everything he could to get us to listen. You are innocent until the court has ruled that you are guilty. He wrote it on the board: a fundamental principle of law. (Samir nodded again.) Christer asked us to take notes. Copy it down. (Samir copied it down. Even though he hardly needed to.)

Christer loved anything short enough to memorize that could be turned into a test question. The correct answer was worth two points on the exam we took two weeks later. Why not one point? Because Christer thought there were gray areas in memorized responses, that you could be almost right. No, one plus one cannot equal three, but I’ll give you partial credit because you answered in the form of a number.

That visit to the court with Christer happened more than two years ago. Sebastian wasn’t there; he wasn’t in our class until our final year, the year he had to repeat. I liked school back then, pretty much, with my classmates and the teachers we’d had in different renditions since our elementary days: the chemistry teacher, Jonas, who spoke too quietly, never remembered anyone’s name, and waited for the bus wearing his backpack on his front. The French teacher, Mari-Louise, with her glasses and dandelion hair, who was always sucking so hard on a tiny sliver of a black lozenge that her mouth became as small and puckered as a wild strawberry. Shorthaired Gym Friggan, who looked like a freshly polished wooden deck: indistinct gender, a whistle around the neck, and broad, shiny, clean-shaven calves, always surrounded by the odor of gym socks and someone else’s sweat. Absentminded Malin, our bottle-blonde math teacher: dissatisfied and constantly late, off sick on average two days a week, and with a photo of herself twenty years slimmer, wearing a string bikini in her profile picture on Facebook.

And Christer Svensson. Dedicated, in a let’s-meet-at-Mariatorget-and-take-a-stand sort of way; ordinary, in a pork-chops-and-mashed-potatoes-and-gravy sort of way. He thought rock concerts could save the world from war, famine, and disease, and he always spoke in that overenthusiastic teacher voice that no one should ever use for anything but getting a dog to wag its tail.

Every day, Christer brought a thermos of home-brewed coffee to school, with so much sugar and milk in it that it looked like liquid foundation. He would pour his coffee into his mug (“World’s Best Dad”) and bring the mug to class and refill it during our lessons. Christer loved routines, same thing every day, favorite song on repeat. He had probably eaten the same thing for breakfast ever since he was fourteen: some sort of cross-country skier thing, like oatmeal with lingonberries and whole milk (“Breakfast is the most important meal of the day!”), I’m sure he drank beer and a shot on the side every time he met up with his friends (“buddies”), ate tacos with his family every Friday, and went to the neighborhood pizzeria (one with crayons and paper for the kids) and split a bottle of the house red with “the wife” when he wanted to celebrate something major and important. Christer had no imagination, he went on charter trips, he would never cook with coriander or fry things in anything but butter.

We first had Christer as a teacher in our first year of upper secondary. He complained at least once a week about how the weather had gotten so strange (“There aren’t seasons anymore”), and every autumn he complained that Christmas decorations went up earlier and earlier (“Soon there will probably be a Christmas tree on Skeppsbron even before the summer ferries stop running.”)

He complained about the evening tabloids (“Why would anyone read that shit?”) and Dancing with the Stars, Eurovision, and Paradise Hotel (“Why would anyone watch that shit?”). Most of all he hated our cell phones (“Are you cows? With those chat apps dinging and jingling constantly, you might as well be wearing bells around your necks…Why do you bother with that shit?”). Every time he complained, he looked pleased, he thought he was youthful and “cool” (not just a Dad word), and that it was proof of how close he was with his students that he could use words like “shit” in front of us.

Christer stuck a pouch of snus under his upper lip after each cup of coffee and collected the used ones in a napkin before throwing them in the trash. Christer liked things neat and tidy, even his garbage.

And afterward, when the tax evader’s trial was over and we went back to the school, he was pleased. He thought we had handled ourselves “well.” Christer was always “pleased” or “concerned,” never overjoyed or totally pissed off. Christer always wanted to give at least partial credit on memorized answers.

Christer was lying down when he died. With his arms around his head and his knees tucked up, more or less how my little sister Lina looks when she’s sleeping most deeply. He bled to death before the ambulance arrived, and I wonder if his wife and his kids feel like things aren’t so simple in reality and that I am innocent because no court has yet determined that I am guilty.

2023-04-15 19:48:01 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:48:01 INFO - Step 26 - Open font settings 2023-04-15 19:48:02 INFO - Button 'btnFontSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:48:03 INFO - Step 27 - Change font style to FONT_SANS 2023-04-15 19:48:03 INFO - Button 'setFontSans' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:48:03 INFO - Step 28 - Book text displays in FONT_SANS font 2023-04-15 19:48:04 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:48:04 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-04-15 19:48:04 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:48:04 INFO -

Week 1 of Trial: Monday

1.

The first time I saw the inside of a courtroom, I was disappointed. We visited one for a class trip, and sure, I had already figured out that Swedish judges aren’t stooping old men in curly wigs and long robes, and that the defendant wouldn’t be a madman in an orange suit, in handcuffs, frothing at the mouth, but still. The place looked like something between a medical clinic and a conference center. We rode there on a rented bus that smelled like bubblegum and sweaty feet. The defendant had dandruff and pleated pants and was allegedly guilty of tax evasion. Aside from our class (and Christer, of course), there were only four other people there to listen, but so few seats that Christer had to get an extra chair from the hallway outside so he had somewhere to sit.

Today it’s different. We’re in the largest courtroom in Sweden. The judges sit on chairs of dark mahogany with high velvet backs. The middle chair’s back is taller than the others’. That’s where the head judge sits. He is called the “chairman.” On the table in front of him is a gavel with a leather handle. Slim microphones stick up before each seat like bent drinking straws. The paneling on the wall looks like oak, like it’s several hundred years old, old in a good way. There is a dark red carpet on the floor between the seats.

Audiences are not my thing. I’ve never wanted to be St. Lucia or take part in talent shows. But it’s packed in here. And everyone is here because of me; I’m the attraction.

Next to me are my attorneys from Sander & Laestadius. I know Sander & Laestadius sounds like an antique shop where two sweaty gay men in silk robes and monocles shuffle around with kerosene lamps dusting off moldy books and taxidermied animals, but it’s Sweden’s best criminal law firm. Ordinary criminals have a single weary public defender; my public defender is flanked by a whole crew of excited wannabe-suits. They work into the wee hours at a super-fancy office near Skeppsbron, have at least two cell phones each, and all of them except Sander himself think that they’re part of an American TV show where you eat Chinese food from take-out cartons in an I’m-so-busy-and-important sort of way. None of all the twenty-two people working at Sander & Laestadius is actually named Laestadius. Laestadius died, I assume of a heart attack, in an I’m-so-busy-and-important sort of way.

Three of my attorneys are here today: Peder Sander, the celebrity, and two of his colleagues. The younger one is a chick with an ugly haircut and a piercing in her nose but no ring in it. Presumably Sander won’t allow her to wear a nose ring (“Remove that junk immediately”). I call her Ferdinand. Ferdinand is the type of person who thinks “conservative” is a curse word and nuclear power is lethal. She wears hideous glasses because she thinks it proves that she’s got the patriarchy all figured out, and she hates me because, in her opinion, capitalism is all my fault. The first few times we met, she treated me like I was a crazy fashion blogger with a hand grenade on an airplane. “Of course, of course!” she said, not daring to look at me. “Of course, of course! Don’t worry, we’re here to help you.” As if I would threaten to blow everyone to bits unless I received my biodynamic tomato juice with no ice.

The other helper attorney is a guy around forty with a doughy belly, a pancake-shaped face, and a smile that says, “I’ve got movies at home that I keep in alphabetical order in a locked cabinet.” Pancake has a buzz cut. Dad likes to say that you can’t trust a person with no hairstyle. But I’m sure Dad didn’t come up with that on his own; he probably stole it from a movie. My dad really likes to deliver one-liners.

The first time I met Pancake, he rested his eyes just below my collarbone, forced his thick tongue back in his mouth, and rasped in delight, “Little girl, what are we going to do? You look much older than seventeen.” He probably would have started panting if Sander hadn’t been there. Or drooling, maybe. Let the saliva drip from his mouth and stain his too-tight suit vest. I couldn’t bring myself to point out that I was eighteen.

Today, Pancake is sitting on my left. He brought a briefcase and a wheeled case stuffed full of folders and documents. He has emptied the case and now the folders are on the table in front of him. The only things he left in the case were a book (Make Your Case—Winning Is the Only Option) and a toothbrush sticking up from one of the little inside pockets. Sitting behind me, in the first row of the audience, are Mom and Dad.

When I was on that class trip two years and an eternity ago, our class had been given a run-through beforehand, so we would “appreciate the importance” and “be able to follow along.” I doubt it helped. But we “behaved,” as Christer said when we left. He had been afraid we wouldn’t be able to keep from giggling and taking out our cell phones. That we were planning to sit there playing games and sleeping with our chins resting on our collars like bored members of Parliament.

I remember Christer’s grave voice as he explained (“Hey now, listen up!”) that a trial is nothing to be flippant about; people’s lives are at stake. You are innocent until the courts have ruled that you are guilty. That’s what he said, several times. Samir leaned back as Christer spoke, balancing on his chair and nodding like he always did, the way that made all the teachers love him. Nods that said I understand completely, we are on the exact same wavelength and I have nothing to add because everything you say is so smart.

You are innocent until the courts have ruled that you are guilty. What kind of weird statement is that? Either you’re innocent all along, or else you did it, right from the start. Shouldn’t the court try to figure out which it is, rather than decide what happened? The police and the prosecutor and the judges weren’t there and don’t know exactly who did what, so how can the court make it up after the fact?

I recall that I pointed this out to Christer. That courts are wrong all the time. Rapists are always going free. There’s not even any point in reporting a sexual assault, because even if you were force-fucked by half a refugee camp and you get an entire case’s worth of bottles shoved up between your legs, they never believe the girl. And that doesn’t mean that it didn’t happen, and that the rapist didn’t do what he did.

“It’s not that simple,” said Christer.

What a typical teacher answer: “That’s an excellent question…” “I hear what you’re saying…” “It’s not black and white…” “It’s not that simple…” Those kinds of answers all mean the same thing: They have no idea what they’re talking about.

But fine. If it’s difficult to know what’s true and who’s lying, if you can’t be sure, then what do you do?

I read somewhere that “the truth is whatever we choose to believe.” Which sounds even more insane, if that’s even possible. Like someone can just decide what’s true and what’s false? Things can be both true and made up, depending on whom you ask? And if someone we trust says something, well, then we can just decide that it’s so, we can “choose that it’s true.” How can anyone even come up with something so idiotic? If a person were to say to me that he “chooses to believe me,” I would know right away that he’s actually convinced that I’m lying but he’s going to pretend otherwise.

My attorney Sander seems mostly indifferent to all of this. All he says is, “I’m on your side,” while his face looks like a thumbnail. Sander is not, like, the excitable type. Everything about him is relaxed and under control. No outbursts. No feelings. No roaring laughter. Probably he didn’t even cry at birth.

Sander is the opposite of my dad. Dad is far from the “cool guy” (his words) he wishes he were. He grinds his teeth in his sleep and jumps to his feet when he watches the national team play soccer. My dad gets mad, furious, at pedantic city employees, the neighbor who parked illegally for the fourth time in one week, incomprehensible electric bills, and telemarketers. Computers, immigration officers, Grandpa, the grill, mosquitoes, unshoveled sidewalks, Germans in the ski-lift line, and French waiters. Everything riles him up, makes him yell and shout, slam doors and tell people to go to hell. With Sander, however, the clearest sign that he’s pissed off, almost insane with anger, is that he gets a wrinkle on his forehead and makes a clicking sound with his tongue. And then all his colleagues become terrified and start stammering and looking for documents and books and other things they think will put him in a better mood. Kind of like how Mom handles Dad on the rare occasions he’s not annoyed but is acting perfectly calm and quiet.

Sander has never gotten mad at me. He’s never been upset over something I told him or grumpy about something I didn’t say or when I was lying and he knew it.

“I’m on your side, Maja.” Sometimes he sounds more tired than usual, but that’s it. “The truth” is not something we talk about.

For the most part, I think it’s nice that Sander only cares about what the police and the prosecutor have proven. I don’t have to worry about whether he is planning to do a good job or is just pretending he’s going to. It’s like he’s taken all the dead and all the guilt and all the agony and turned it into numbers, and if the equations don’t add up, then he wins.

Maybe that’s how it should be done. One plus one cannot equal three. Next question, please.

But that’s of no help to me, of course. Because either something happened or it didn’t. It is what it is. All the rest is just beating around the bush, the kind of thing that philosophers do, as well as (apparently) a lawyer here and there. Constructs. “It’s not that simple…”

But Christer, I remember how insistent he was before that court visit, he really did everything he could to get us to listen. You are innocent until the court has ruled that you are guilty. He wrote it on the board: a fundamental principle of law. (Samir nodded again.) Christer asked us to take notes. Copy it down. (Samir copied it down. Even though he hardly needed to.)

Christer loved anything short enough to memorize that could be turned into a test question. The correct answer was worth two points on the exam we took two weeks later. Why not one point? Because Christer thought there were gray areas in memorized responses, that you could be almost right. No, one plus one cannot equal three, but I’ll give you partial credit because you answered in the form of a number.

That visit to the court with Christer happened more than two years ago. Sebastian wasn’t there; he wasn’t in our class until our final year, the year he had to repeat. I liked school back then, pretty much, with my classmates and the teachers we’d had in different renditions since our elementary days: the chemistry teacher, Jonas, who spoke too quietly, never remembered anyone’s name, and waited for the bus wearing his backpack on his front. The French teacher, Mari-Louise, with her glasses and dandelion hair, who was always sucking so hard on a tiny sliver of a black lozenge that her mouth became as small and puckered as a wild strawberry. Shorthaired Gym Friggan, who looked like a freshly polished wooden deck: indistinct gender, a whistle around the neck, and broad, shiny, clean-shaven calves, always surrounded by the odor of gym socks and someone else’s sweat. Absentminded Malin, our bottle-blonde math teacher: dissatisfied and constantly late, off sick on average two days a week, and with a photo of herself twenty years slimmer, wearing a string bikini in her profile picture on Facebook.

And Christer Svensson. Dedicated, in a let’s-meet-at-Mariatorget-and-take-a-stand sort of way; ordinary, in a pork-chops-and-mashed-potatoes-and-gravy sort of way. He thought rock concerts could save the world from war, famine, and disease, and he always spoke in that overenthusiastic teacher voice that no one should ever use for anything but getting a dog to wag its tail.

Every day, Christer brought a thermos of home-brewed coffee to school, with so much sugar and milk in it that it looked like liquid foundation. He would pour his coffee into his mug (“World’s Best Dad”) and bring the mug to class and refill it during our lessons. Christer loved routines, same thing every day, favorite song on repeat. He had probably eaten the same thing for breakfast ever since he was fourteen: some sort of cross-country skier thing, like oatmeal with lingonberries and whole milk (“Breakfast is the most important meal of the day!”), I’m sure he drank beer and a shot on the side every time he met up with his friends (“buddies”), ate tacos with his family every Friday, and went to the neighborhood pizzeria (one with crayons and paper for the kids) and split a bottle of the house red with “the wife” when he wanted to celebrate something major and important. Christer had no imagination, he went on charter trips, he would never cook with coriander or fry things in anything but butter.

We first had Christer as a teacher in our first year of upper secondary. He complained at least once a week about how the weather had gotten so strange (“There aren’t seasons anymore”), and every autumn he complained that Christmas decorations went up earlier and earlier (“Soon there will probably be a Christmas tree on Skeppsbron even before the summer ferries stop running.”)

He complained about the evening tabloids (“Why would anyone read that shit?”) and Dancing with the Stars, Eurovision, and Paradise Hotel (“Why would anyone watch that shit?”). Most of all he hated our cell phones (“Are you cows? With those chat apps dinging and jingling constantly, you might as well be wearing bells around your necks…Why do you bother with that shit?”). Every time he complained, he looked pleased, he thought he was youthful and “cool” (not just a Dad word), and that it was proof of how close he was with his students that he could use words like “shit” in front of us.

Christer stuck a pouch of snus under his upper lip after each cup of coffee and collected the used ones in a napkin before throwing them in the trash. Christer liked things neat and tidy, even his garbage.

And afterward, when the tax evader’s trial was over and we went back to the school, he was pleased. He thought we had handled ourselves “well.” Christer was always “pleased” or “concerned,” never overjoyed or totally pissed off. Christer always wanted to give at least partial credit on memorized answers.

Christer was lying down when he died. With his arms around his head and his knees tucked up, more or less how my little sister Lina looks when she’s sleeping most deeply. He bled to death before the ambulance arrived, and I wonder if his wife and his kids feel like things aren’t so simple in reality and that I am innocent because no court has yet determined that I am guilty.

2023-04-15 19:48:04 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:48:05 INFO - Taking screenshot 2023-04-15 19:48:06 INFO - Test finished - logging out 2023-04-15 19:48:07 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:48:09 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:48:10 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:48:12 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:48:13 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:48:13 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:48:14 INFO - Button 'Log out' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:48:34 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:48:34 INFO - Unlocking credential for current thread 2023-04-15 19:48:34 INFO - isLoggerNullAfterAnnotation-framework.utilities.Logger@3d34f997

2023-04-15 19:40:35 INFO - Scenario 'Font settings: Check of font style' start 2023-04-15 19:40:35 INFO - Setting application driver using the server on 'https://hub-cloud.browserstack.com/wd/hub' 2023-04-15 19:41:06 INFO - Application on platform 'ANDROID' is ready... 2023-04-15 19:41:06 INFO - Session id - 470c3dd255b46b2cb3745c34f527d9908f1b5531 2023-04-15 19:41:06 INFO - Step 0 - Close tutorial screen 2023-04-15 19:41:06 INFO - Button 'btnCloseTutorial' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:41:09 INFO - Step 1 - Welcome screen is opened 2023-04-15 19:41:10 INFO - Step 2 - Close welcome screen 2023-04-15 19:41:10 INFO - Button 'btnFindLibrary' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:41:10 INFO - Step 3 - Add library screen is opened 2023-04-15 19:41:11 INFO - Step 4 - Add library "LYRASIS Reads" on Add library screen 2023-04-15 19:41:12 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:41:13 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Clearing 2023-04-15 19:41:13 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Typing 'LYRASIS Reads' 2023-04-15 19:41:15 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:41:16 INFO - Step 5 - Account "LYRASIS Reads" is present on Accounts screen 2023-04-15 19:41:16 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:41:17 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:41:18 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:41:20 INFO - Step 6 - Enter credentials for 'LYRASIS Reads' account 2023-04-15 19:41:20 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:41:20 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:41:22 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:41:22 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:41:23 INFO - Locking credential with barcode 01230000000004 2023-04-15 19:41:23 INFO - There are books on the account: 2023-04-15 19:41:24 INFO - bookName: How the Word Is Passed Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-04-15 19:41:24 INFO - bookName: Dream Hoarders Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-04-15 19:41:24 INFO - bookName: The Great Displacement Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-04-15 19:41:24 INFO - Count of books on the account after opening account: 3 2023-04-15 19:41:24 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Clearing 2023-04-15 19:41:24 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Typing '01230000000004' 2023-04-15 19:41:26 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Clearing 2023-04-15 19:41:26 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Typing '********' 2023-04-15 19:41:28 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:41:34 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:41:34 INFO - Step 7 - Login is performed successfully 2023-04-15 19:41:55 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:41:55 INFO - Step 8 - Open Catalog 2023-04-15 19:41:55 INFO - Button 'tabCatalog' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:42:17 INFO - Step 9 - Open search modal 2023-04-15 19:42:37 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:42:39 INFO - Step 10 - Search 'available' book of distributor 'Palace Marketplace' and bookType 'EBOOK' from "LYRASIS Reads" and save as 'bookNameInfo' 2023-04-15 19:42:39 INFO - Count of attempts to get random book name without bad symbols-1 2023-04-15 19:42:39 INFO - randomBookName: The Expressman and the Detective 2023-04-15 19:42:39 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-04-15 19:42:39 INFO - Text Field 'Search value input' :: Sending keys 'The Expressman and the Detective' 2023-04-15 19:42:41 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-04-15 19:42:44 INFO - Step 11 - Click GET action button on EBOOK book with 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-04-15 19:42:45 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:42:47 INFO - Button 'actionButton' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:42:54 INFO - Step 12 - Open EBOOK book with READ action button and 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-04-15 19:42:54 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:42:55 INFO - Label 'lblBookName' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:42:55 INFO - Step 13 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-04-15 19:42:56 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:42:56 INFO - Step 14 - Scroll page forward from 7 to 9 times 2023-04-15 19:42:56 INFO - Scrolling 8 times on reader epub screen 2023-04-15 19:43:15 INFO - Step 15 - Open font settings 2023-04-15 19:43:16 INFO - Button 'btnFontSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:43:16 INFO - Step 16 - Change font style to FONT_SERIF 2023-04-15 19:43:16 INFO - Button 'setFontSerif' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:43:17 INFO - Step 17 - Book text displays in FONT_SERIF font 2023-04-15 19:43:17 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:43:17 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-04-15 19:43:18 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:43:18 INFO -

Chapter I.

Montgomery, Alabama, is beautifully situated on the Alabama river, near the centre of the State. Its situation at the head of navigation, on the Alabama river, its connection by rail with important points, and the rich agricultural country with which it is surrounded, make it a great commercial centre, and the second city in the State as regards wealth and population. It is the capital, and consequently learned men and great politicians flock to it, giving it a society of the highest rank, and making it the social centre of the State.

From 1858 to 1860, the time of which I treat in the present work, the South was in a most prosperous condition. "Cotton was king," and millions of dollars were poured into the country for its purchase, and a fair share of this money found its way to Montgomery.

When the Alabama planters had gathered their crops of cotton, tobacco, rice, etc., they sent them to Montgomery to be sold, and placed the proceeds on deposit in its banks. During their busy season, while overseeing the labor of their slaves, they were almost entirely debarred from the society of any but their own families; but when the crops were gathered they went with their families to Montgomery, where they gave themselves up to enjoyment, spending their money in a most lavish manner.

There were several good hotels in the city and they were always filled to overflowing with the wealth and beauty of the South.

The Adams Express Company had a monopoly of the express business of the South, and had established its agencies at all points with which there was communication by rail, steam or stage. They handled all the money sent to the South for the purchase of produce, or remitted to the North in payment of merchandise. Moreover, as they did all the express business for the banks, besides moving an immense amount of freight, it is evident that their business was enormous.

At all points of importance, where there were diverging routes of communication, the company had established principal agencies, at which all through freight and the money pouches were delivered by the messengers. The agents at these points were selected with the greatest care, and were always considered men above reproach. Montgomery being a great centre of trade was made the western terminus of one of the express routes, Atlanta being the eastern. The messengers who had charge of the express matter between these two points were each provided with a safe and with a pouch. The latter was to contain only such packages as were to go over the whole route, consisting of money or other valuables. The messenger was not furnished with a key to the pouch, but it was handed to him locked by the agent at one end of the route to be delivered in the same condition to the agent at the other end.

The safe was intended for way packages, and of it the messenger of course had a key. The pouch was carried in the safe, each being protected by a lock of peculiar construction.

The Montgomery office in 1858, and for some years previous, had been in charge of Nathan Maroney, and he had made himself one of the most popular agents in the company's employ.

He was married, and with his wife and one daughter, had pleasant quarters at the Exchange Hotel, one of the best houses in the city. He possessed all the qualifications which make a popular man. He had a genial, hearty manner, which endeared him to the open, hospitable inhabitants of Montgomery, so that he was "hail fellow, well met," with most of its populace. He possessed great executive ability and hence managed the affairs of his office in a very satisfactory manner. The promptness with which he discharged his duties had won for him the well-merited esteem of the officers of the company, and he was in a fair way of attaining a still higher position. His greatest weakness—if it may be so called—was a love for fast horses, which often threw him into the company of betting men.

On the morning of the twenty-sixth of April, 1858, the messenger from Atlanta arrived in Montgomery, placed his safe in the office as usual, and when Maroney came in, turned over to him the through pouch.

Maroney unlocked the pouch and compared it with the way-bill, when he discovered a package of four thousand seven hundred and fifty dollars for a party in Montgomery which was not down on the way-bill. About a week after this occurrence, advice was received that a package containing ten thousand dollars in bills of the Planters' and Mechanics' Bank of Charleston, S. C., had been sent to Columbus, Ga., via the Adams Express, but the person to whom it was directed had not received it. Inquiries were at once instituted, when it was discovered that it had been missent, and forwarded to Atlanta, instead of Macon. At Atlanta it was recollected that this package, together with one for Montgomery, for four thousand seven hundred and fifty dollars, had been received on Sunday, the twenty-fifth of April, and had been sent on to Montgomery, whence the Columbus package could be forwarded the next day. Here all trace of the missing package was lost. Maroney stated positively that he had not received it, and the messenger was equally positive that the pouch had been delivered to Maroney in the same order in which he received it from the Atlanta agent.

The officers of the company were completely at a loss. It was discovered beyond a doubt that the package had been sent from Atlanta. The messenger who received it bore an excellent character, and the company could not believe him guilty of the theft. The lock of the pouch was examined and found in perfect order, so that it evidently had not been tampered with. The messenger was positive that he had not left the safe open when he went out of the car, and there was no sign of the lock's having been forced.

The more the case was investigated, the more directly did suspicion point to Maroney, but as his integrity had always been unquestioned, no one now was willing to admit the possibility of his guilt. However, as no decided action in the matter could be taken, it was determined to say nothing, but to have the movements of Maroney and other suspected parties closely watched.

For this purpose various detectives were employed; one a local detective of Montgomery, named McGibony; others from New Orleans, Philadelphia, Mobile, and New York. After a long investigation these parties had to give up the case as hopeless, all concluding that Maroney was an innocent man. Among the detectives, however was one from New York, Robert Boyer, by name, an old and favorite officer of Mr. Matsell when he was chief of the New York police. He had made a long and tedious examination and finding nothing definite as to what had become of the money, had turned his attention to discovering the antecedents of Maroney, but found nothing positively suspicious in his life previous to his entering the employ of the company. He discovered that Maroney was the son of a physician, and that he was born in the town of Rome, Ga.

Here I would remark that the number of titled men one meets in the South is astonishing. Every man, if he is not a doctor, a lawyer, or a clergyman, has some military title—nothing lower than captain being admissible. Of these self-imposed titles they are very jealous, and woe be to the man who neglects to address them in the proper form. Captain is the general title, and is applied indiscriminately to the captain of a steamer, or to the deck hand on his vessel.

Maroney remained in Rome until he became a young man, when he emigrated to Texas. On the breaking out of the Mexican war he joined a company of Texan Rangers, and distinguished himself in a number of battles. At the close of the war he settled in Montgomery, in the year 1851, or 1852, and was employed by Hampton & Co., owners of a line of stages, to act as their agent. On leaving this position, he was made treasurer of Johnson & May's circus, remaining with the company until it was disbanded in consequence of the pecuniary difficulties of the proprietors—caused, it was alleged, through Maroney's embezzlement of the funds, though this allegation proved false, and he remained for many years on terms of intimacy with one of the partners, a resident of Montgomery. When the company disbanded he obtained a situation as conductor on a railroad in Tennessee, and was afterwards made Assistant Superintendent, which position he resigned to take the agency of the Adams Express Company, in Montgomery. His whole life seemed spotless up to the time of the mysterious disappearance of the ten thousand dollars.

In the fall of the year, Maroney obtained leave of absence, and made a trip to the North, visiting the principal cities of the East, and also of the Northwest. He was followed on this trip, but nothing was discovered, with the single exception that his associates were not always such as were desirable in an employé, to whose keeping very heavy interests were from time to time necessarily committed. He was lost sight of at Richmond, Va., for a few days, and was supposed by the man who was following him, to have passed the time in Charleston.

The company now gave up all hope of recovering the money; but as Maroney's habits were expensive, and they had lost, somewhat, their confidence in him, they determined to remove him and place some less objectionable person in his place.

Maroney's passion for fine horses has already been alluded to. It was stated about this time that he owned several fast horses; among others, "Yankee Mary," a horse for which he was said to have paid two thousand five hundred dollars; but as he had brought seven thousand five hundred dollars with him when he entered the employ of the company, this could not be considered a suspicious circumstance.

It having been determined to remove Maroney, the Vice-President of the company wrote to the Superintendent of the Southern Division of the steps he wished taken. The Superintendent of the Southern Division visited Montgomery on the twentieth of January, 1859, but was anticipated in the matter of carrying out his instructions, by Maroney's tendering his resignation. The resignation was accepted, but the superintendent requested him to continue in charge of the office until his successor should arrive.

This he consented to do.

2023-04-15 19:43:18 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:43:19 INFO - Step 18 - Restart app 2023-04-15 19:43:43 INFO - Step 19 - Open Books 2023-04-15 19:43:43 INFO - Button 'tabBooks' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:43:45 INFO - Step 20 - Open EBOOK book with READ action button and 'bookInfo' bookInfo on books screen 2023-04-15 19:43:45 INFO - Label 'lblBookName' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:43:45 INFO - Step 21 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-04-15 19:43:46 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:43:46 INFO - Step 22 - Book text displays in FONT_SERIF font 2023-04-15 19:43:47 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:43:48 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:43:49 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:43:49 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-04-15 19:43:50 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:43:50 INFO -

Chapter I.

Montgomery, Alabama, is beautifully situated on the Alabama river, near the centre of the State. Its situation at the head of navigation, on the Alabama river, its connection by rail with important points, and the rich agricultural country with which it is surrounded, make it a great commercial centre, and the second city in the State as regards wealth and population. It is the capital, and consequently learned men and great politicians flock to it, giving it a society of the highest rank, and making it the social centre of the State.

From 1858 to 1860, the time of which I treat in the present work, the South was in a most prosperous condition. "Cotton was king," and millions of dollars were poured into the country for its purchase, and a fair share of this money found its way to Montgomery.

When the Alabama planters had gathered their crops of cotton, tobacco, rice, etc., they sent them to Montgomery to be sold, and placed the proceeds on deposit in its banks. During their busy season, while overseeing the labor of their slaves, they were almost entirely debarred from the society of any but their own families; but when the crops were gathered they went with their families to Montgomery, where they gave themselves up to enjoyment, spending their money in a most lavish manner.

There were several good hotels in the city and they were always filled to overflowing with the wealth and beauty of the South.

The Adams Express Company had a monopoly of the express business of the South, and had established its agencies at all points with which there was communication by rail, steam or stage. They handled all the money sent to the South for the purchase of produce, or remitted to the North in payment of merchandise. Moreover, as they did all the express business for the banks, besides moving an immense amount of freight, it is evident that their business was enormous.

At all points of importance, where there were diverging routes of communication, the company had established principal agencies, at which all through freight and the money pouches were delivered by the messengers. The agents at these points were selected with the greatest care, and were always considered men above reproach. Montgomery being a great centre of trade was made the western terminus of one of the express routes, Atlanta being the eastern. The messengers who had charge of the express matter between these two points were each provided with a safe and with a pouch. The latter was to contain only such packages as were to go over the whole route, consisting of money or other valuables. The messenger was not furnished with a key to the pouch, but it was handed to him locked by the agent at one end of the route to be delivered in the same condition to the agent at the other end.

The safe was intended for way packages, and of it the messenger of course had a key. The pouch was carried in the safe, each being protected by a lock of peculiar construction.

The Montgomery office in 1858, and for some years previous, had been in charge of Nathan Maroney, and he had made himself one of the most popular agents in the company's employ.

He was married, and with his wife and one daughter, had pleasant quarters at the Exchange Hotel, one of the best houses in the city. He possessed all the qualifications which make a popular man. He had a genial, hearty manner, which endeared him to the open, hospitable inhabitants of Montgomery, so that he was "hail fellow, well met," with most of its populace. He possessed great executive ability and hence managed the affairs of his office in a very satisfactory manner. The promptness with which he discharged his duties had won for him the well-merited esteem of the officers of the company, and he was in a fair way of attaining a still higher position. His greatest weakness—if it may be so called—was a love for fast horses, which often threw him into the company of betting men.

On the morning of the twenty-sixth of April, 1858, the messenger from Atlanta arrived in Montgomery, placed his safe in the office as usual, and when Maroney came in, turned over to him the through pouch.

Maroney unlocked the pouch and compared it with the way-bill, when he discovered a package of four thousand seven hundred and fifty dollars for a party in Montgomery which was not down on the way-bill. About a week after this occurrence, advice was received that a package containing ten thousand dollars in bills of the Planters' and Mechanics' Bank of Charleston, S. C., had been sent to Columbus, Ga., via the Adams Express, but the person to whom it was directed had not received it. Inquiries were at once instituted, when it was discovered that it had been missent, and forwarded to Atlanta, instead of Macon. At Atlanta it was recollected that this package, together with one for Montgomery, for four thousand seven hundred and fifty dollars, had been received on Sunday, the twenty-fifth of April, and had been sent on to Montgomery, whence the Columbus package could be forwarded the next day. Here all trace of the missing package was lost. Maroney stated positively that he had not received it, and the messenger was equally positive that the pouch had been delivered to Maroney in the same order in which he received it from the Atlanta agent.

The officers of the company were completely at a loss. It was discovered beyond a doubt that the package had been sent from Atlanta. The messenger who received it bore an excellent character, and the company could not believe him guilty of the theft. The lock of the pouch was examined and found in perfect order, so that it evidently had not been tampered with. The messenger was positive that he had not left the safe open when he went out of the car, and there was no sign of the lock's having been forced.

The more the case was investigated, the more directly did suspicion point to Maroney, but as his integrity had always been unquestioned, no one now was willing to admit the possibility of his guilt. However, as no decided action in the matter could be taken, it was determined to say nothing, but to have the movements of Maroney and other suspected parties closely watched.

For this purpose various detectives were employed; one a local detective of Montgomery, named McGibony; others from New Orleans, Philadelphia, Mobile, and New York. After a long investigation these parties had to give up the case as hopeless, all concluding that Maroney was an innocent man. Among the detectives, however was one from New York, Robert Boyer, by name, an old and favorite officer of Mr. Matsell when he was chief of the New York police. He had made a long and tedious examination and finding nothing definite as to what had become of the money, had turned his attention to discovering the antecedents of Maroney, but found nothing positively suspicious in his life previous to his entering the employ of the company. He discovered that Maroney was the son of a physician, and that he was born in the town of Rome, Ga.

Here I would remark that the number of titled men one meets in the South is astonishing. Every man, if he is not a doctor, a lawyer, or a clergyman, has some military title—nothing lower than captain being admissible. Of these self-imposed titles they are very jealous, and woe be to the man who neglects to address them in the proper form. Captain is the general title, and is applied indiscriminately to the captain of a steamer, or to the deck hand on his vessel.

Maroney remained in Rome until he became a young man, when he emigrated to Texas. On the breaking out of the Mexican war he joined a company of Texan Rangers, and distinguished himself in a number of battles. At the close of the war he settled in Montgomery, in the year 1851, or 1852, and was employed by Hampton & Co., owners of a line of stages, to act as their agent. On leaving this position, he was made treasurer of Johnson & May's circus, remaining with the company until it was disbanded in consequence of the pecuniary difficulties of the proprietors—caused, it was alleged, through Maroney's embezzlement of the funds, though this allegation proved false, and he remained for many years on terms of intimacy with one of the partners, a resident of Montgomery. When the company disbanded he obtained a situation as conductor on a railroad in Tennessee, and was afterwards made Assistant Superintendent, which position he resigned to take the agency of the Adams Express Company, in Montgomery. His whole life seemed spotless up to the time of the mysterious disappearance of the ten thousand dollars.

In the fall of the year, Maroney obtained leave of absence, and made a trip to the North, visiting the principal cities of the East, and also of the Northwest. He was followed on this trip, but nothing was discovered, with the single exception that his associates were not always such as were desirable in an employé, to whose keeping very heavy interests were from time to time necessarily committed. He was lost sight of at Richmond, Va., for a few days, and was supposed by the man who was following him, to have passed the time in Charleston.

The company now gave up all hope of recovering the money; but as Maroney's habits were expensive, and they had lost, somewhat, their confidence in him, they determined to remove him and place some less objectionable person in his place.

Maroney's passion for fine horses has already been alluded to. It was stated about this time that he owned several fast horses; among others, "Yankee Mary," a horse for which he was said to have paid two thousand five hundred dollars; but as he had brought seven thousand five hundred dollars with him when he entered the employ of the company, this could not be considered a suspicious circumstance.

It having been determined to remove Maroney, the Vice-President of the company wrote to the Superintendent of the Southern Division of the steps he wished taken. The Superintendent of the Southern Division visited Montgomery on the twentieth of January, 1859, but was anticipated in the matter of carrying out his instructions, by Maroney's tendering his resignation. The resignation was accepted, but the superintendent requested him to continue in charge of the office until his successor should arrive.

This he consented to do.

2023-04-15 19:43:50 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:43:50 INFO - Step 23 - Return to previous screen from epub 2023-04-15 19:43:51 INFO - Button 'btnBack' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:43:51 INFO - Step 24 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-04-15 19:43:52 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:43:53 INFO - Step 25 - Book text displays in FONT_SERIF font 2023-04-15 19:43:53 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:43:53 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-04-15 19:43:54 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:43:54 INFO -

Chapter I.

Montgomery, Alabama, is beautifully situated on the Alabama river, near the centre of the State. Its situation at the head of navigation, on the Alabama river, its connection by rail with important points, and the rich agricultural country with which it is surrounded, make it a great commercial centre, and the second city in the State as regards wealth and population. It is the capital, and consequently learned men and great politicians flock to it, giving it a society of the highest rank, and making it the social centre of the State.

From 1858 to 1860, the time of which I treat in the present work, the South was in a most prosperous condition. "Cotton was king," and millions of dollars were poured into the country for its purchase, and a fair share of this money found its way to Montgomery.

When the Alabama planters had gathered their crops of cotton, tobacco, rice, etc., they sent them to Montgomery to be sold, and placed the proceeds on deposit in its banks. During their busy season, while overseeing the labor of their slaves, they were almost entirely debarred from the society of any but their own families; but when the crops were gathered they went with their families to Montgomery, where they gave themselves up to enjoyment, spending their money in a most lavish manner.

There were several good hotels in the city and they were always filled to overflowing with the wealth and beauty of the South.

The Adams Express Company had a monopoly of the express business of the South, and had established its agencies at all points with which there was communication by rail, steam or stage. They handled all the money sent to the South for the purchase of produce, or remitted to the North in payment of merchandise. Moreover, as they did all the express business for the banks, besides moving an immense amount of freight, it is evident that their business was enormous.

At all points of importance, where there were diverging routes of communication, the company had established principal agencies, at which all through freight and the money pouches were delivered by the messengers. The agents at these points were selected with the greatest care, and were always considered men above reproach. Montgomery being a great centre of trade was made the western terminus of one of the express routes, Atlanta being the eastern. The messengers who had charge of the express matter between these two points were each provided with a safe and with a pouch. The latter was to contain only such packages as were to go over the whole route, consisting of money or other valuables. The messenger was not furnished with a key to the pouch, but it was handed to him locked by the agent at one end of the route to be delivered in the same condition to the agent at the other end.

The safe was intended for way packages, and of it the messenger of course had a key. The pouch was carried in the safe, each being protected by a lock of peculiar construction.

The Montgomery office in 1858, and for some years previous, had been in charge of Nathan Maroney, and he had made himself one of the most popular agents in the company's employ.

He was married, and with his wife and one daughter, had pleasant quarters at the Exchange Hotel, one of the best houses in the city. He possessed all the qualifications which make a popular man. He had a genial, hearty manner, which endeared him to the open, hospitable inhabitants of Montgomery, so that he was "hail fellow, well met," with most of its populace. He possessed great executive ability and hence managed the affairs of his office in a very satisfactory manner. The promptness with which he discharged his duties had won for him the well-merited esteem of the officers of the company, and he was in a fair way of attaining a still higher position. His greatest weakness—if it may be so called—was a love for fast horses, which often threw him into the company of betting men.

On the morning of the twenty-sixth of April, 1858, the messenger from Atlanta arrived in Montgomery, placed his safe in the office as usual, and when Maroney came in, turned over to him the through pouch.

Maroney unlocked the pouch and compared it with the way-bill, when he discovered a package of four thousand seven hundred and fifty dollars for a party in Montgomery which was not down on the way-bill. About a week after this occurrence, advice was received that a package containing ten thousand dollars in bills of the Planters' and Mechanics' Bank of Charleston, S. C., had been sent to Columbus, Ga., via the Adams Express, but the person to whom it was directed had not received it. Inquiries were at once instituted, when it was discovered that it had been missent, and forwarded to Atlanta, instead of Macon. At Atlanta it was recollected that this package, together with one for Montgomery, for four thousand seven hundred and fifty dollars, had been received on Sunday, the twenty-fifth of April, and had been sent on to Montgomery, whence the Columbus package could be forwarded the next day. Here all trace of the missing package was lost. Maroney stated positively that he had not received it, and the messenger was equally positive that the pouch had been delivered to Maroney in the same order in which he received it from the Atlanta agent.

The officers of the company were completely at a loss. It was discovered beyond a doubt that the package had been sent from Atlanta. The messenger who received it bore an excellent character, and the company could not believe him guilty of the theft. The lock of the pouch was examined and found in perfect order, so that it evidently had not been tampered with. The messenger was positive that he had not left the safe open when he went out of the car, and there was no sign of the lock's having been forced.

The more the case was investigated, the more directly did suspicion point to Maroney, but as his integrity had always been unquestioned, no one now was willing to admit the possibility of his guilt. However, as no decided action in the matter could be taken, it was determined to say nothing, but to have the movements of Maroney and other suspected parties closely watched.

For this purpose various detectives were employed; one a local detective of Montgomery, named McGibony; others from New Orleans, Philadelphia, Mobile, and New York. After a long investigation these parties had to give up the case as hopeless, all concluding that Maroney was an innocent man. Among the detectives, however was one from New York, Robert Boyer, by name, an old and favorite officer of Mr. Matsell when he was chief of the New York police. He had made a long and tedious examination and finding nothing definite as to what had become of the money, had turned his attention to discovering the antecedents of Maroney, but found nothing positively suspicious in his life previous to his entering the employ of the company. He discovered that Maroney was the son of a physician, and that he was born in the town of Rome, Ga.

Here I would remark that the number of titled men one meets in the South is astonishing. Every man, if he is not a doctor, a lawyer, or a clergyman, has some military title—nothing lower than captain being admissible. Of these self-imposed titles they are very jealous, and woe be to the man who neglects to address them in the proper form. Captain is the general title, and is applied indiscriminately to the captain of a steamer, or to the deck hand on his vessel.

Maroney remained in Rome until he became a young man, when he emigrated to Texas. On the breaking out of the Mexican war he joined a company of Texan Rangers, and distinguished himself in a number of battles. At the close of the war he settled in Montgomery, in the year 1851, or 1852, and was employed by Hampton & Co., owners of a line of stages, to act as their agent. On leaving this position, he was made treasurer of Johnson & May's circus, remaining with the company until it was disbanded in consequence of the pecuniary difficulties of the proprietors—caused, it was alleged, through Maroney's embezzlement of the funds, though this allegation proved false, and he remained for many years on terms of intimacy with one of the partners, a resident of Montgomery. When the company disbanded he obtained a situation as conductor on a railroad in Tennessee, and was afterwards made Assistant Superintendent, which position he resigned to take the agency of the Adams Express Company, in Montgomery. His whole life seemed spotless up to the time of the mysterious disappearance of the ten thousand dollars.

In the fall of the year, Maroney obtained leave of absence, and made a trip to the North, visiting the principal cities of the East, and also of the Northwest. He was followed on this trip, but nothing was discovered, with the single exception that his associates were not always such as were desirable in an employé, to whose keeping very heavy interests were from time to time necessarily committed. He was lost sight of at Richmond, Va., for a few days, and was supposed by the man who was following him, to have passed the time in Charleston.

The company now gave up all hope of recovering the money; but as Maroney's habits were expensive, and they had lost, somewhat, their confidence in him, they determined to remove him and place some less objectionable person in his place.

Maroney's passion for fine horses has already been alluded to. It was stated about this time that he owned several fast horses; among others, "Yankee Mary," a horse for which he was said to have paid two thousand five hundred dollars; but as he had brought seven thousand five hundred dollars with him when he entered the employ of the company, this could not be considered a suspicious circumstance.

It having been determined to remove Maroney, the Vice-President of the company wrote to the Superintendent of the Southern Division of the steps he wished taken. The Superintendent of the Southern Division visited Montgomery on the twentieth of January, 1859, but was anticipated in the matter of carrying out his instructions, by Maroney's tendering his resignation. The resignation was accepted, but the superintendent requested him to continue in charge of the office until his successor should arrive.

This he consented to do.

2023-04-15 19:43:54 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:43:55 INFO - Step 26 - Open font settings 2023-04-15 19:43:56 INFO - Button 'btnFontSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:43:56 INFO - Step 27 - Change font style to FONT_SANS 2023-04-15 19:43:56 INFO - Button 'setFontSans' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:43:58 INFO - Step 28 - Book text displays in FONT_SANS font 2023-04-15 19:43:58 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-04-15 19:43:58 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-04-15 19:43:58 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:43:58 INFO -

Chapter I.

Montgomery, Alabama, is beautifully situated on the Alabama river, near the centre of the State. Its situation at the head of navigation, on the Alabama river, its connection by rail with important points, and the rich agricultural country with which it is surrounded, make it a great commercial centre, and the second city in the State as regards wealth and population. It is the capital, and consequently learned men and great politicians flock to it, giving it a society of the highest rank, and making it the social centre of the State.

From 1858 to 1860, the time of which I treat in the present work, the South was in a most prosperous condition. "Cotton was king," and millions of dollars were poured into the country for its purchase, and a fair share of this money found its way to Montgomery.

When the Alabama planters had gathered their crops of cotton, tobacco, rice, etc., they sent them to Montgomery to be sold, and placed the proceeds on deposit in its banks. During their busy season, while overseeing the labor of their slaves, they were almost entirely debarred from the society of any but their own families; but when the crops were gathered they went with their families to Montgomery, where they gave themselves up to enjoyment, spending their money in a most lavish manner.

There were several good hotels in the city and they were always filled to overflowing with the wealth and beauty of the South.

The Adams Express Company had a monopoly of the express business of the South, and had established its agencies at all points with which there was communication by rail, steam or stage. They handled all the money sent to the South for the purchase of produce, or remitted to the North in payment of merchandise. Moreover, as they did all the express business for the banks, besides moving an immense amount of freight, it is evident that their business was enormous.

At all points of importance, where there were diverging routes of communication, the company had established principal agencies, at which all through freight and the money pouches were delivered by the messengers. The agents at these points were selected with the greatest care, and were always considered men above reproach. Montgomery being a great centre of trade was made the western terminus of one of the express routes, Atlanta being the eastern. The messengers who had charge of the express matter between these two points were each provided with a safe and with a pouch. The latter was to contain only such packages as were to go over the whole route, consisting of money or other valuables. The messenger was not furnished with a key to the pouch, but it was handed to him locked by the agent at one end of the route to be delivered in the same condition to the agent at the other end.

The safe was intended for way packages, and of it the messenger of course had a key. The pouch was carried in the safe, each being protected by a lock of peculiar construction.

The Montgomery office in 1858, and for some years previous, had been in charge of Nathan Maroney, and he had made himself one of the most popular agents in the company's employ.

He was married, and with his wife and one daughter, had pleasant quarters at the Exchange Hotel, one of the best houses in the city. He possessed all the qualifications which make a popular man. He had a genial, hearty manner, which endeared him to the open, hospitable inhabitants of Montgomery, so that he was "hail fellow, well met," with most of its populace. He possessed great executive ability and hence managed the affairs of his office in a very satisfactory manner. The promptness with which he discharged his duties had won for him the well-merited esteem of the officers of the company, and he was in a fair way of attaining a still higher position. His greatest weakness—if it may be so called—was a love for fast horses, which often threw him into the company of betting men.

On the morning of the twenty-sixth of April, 1858, the messenger from Atlanta arrived in Montgomery, placed his safe in the office as usual, and when Maroney came in, turned over to him the through pouch.

Maroney unlocked the pouch and compared it with the way-bill, when he discovered a package of four thousand seven hundred and fifty dollars for a party in Montgomery which was not down on the way-bill. About a week after this occurrence, advice was received that a package containing ten thousand dollars in bills of the Planters' and Mechanics' Bank of Charleston, S. C., had been sent to Columbus, Ga., via the Adams Express, but the person to whom it was directed had not received it. Inquiries were at once instituted, when it was discovered that it had been missent, and forwarded to Atlanta, instead of Macon. At Atlanta it was recollected that this package, together with one for Montgomery, for four thousand seven hundred and fifty dollars, had been received on Sunday, the twenty-fifth of April, and had been sent on to Montgomery, whence the Columbus package could be forwarded the next day. Here all trace of the missing package was lost. Maroney stated positively that he had not received it, and the messenger was equally positive that the pouch had been delivered to Maroney in the same order in which he received it from the Atlanta agent.

The officers of the company were completely at a loss. It was discovered beyond a doubt that the package had been sent from Atlanta. The messenger who received it bore an excellent character, and the company could not believe him guilty of the theft. The lock of the pouch was examined and found in perfect order, so that it evidently had not been tampered with. The messenger was positive that he had not left the safe open when he went out of the car, and there was no sign of the lock's having been forced.

The more the case was investigated, the more directly did suspicion point to Maroney, but as his integrity had always been unquestioned, no one now was willing to admit the possibility of his guilt. However, as no decided action in the matter could be taken, it was determined to say nothing, but to have the movements of Maroney and other suspected parties closely watched.

For this purpose various detectives were employed; one a local detective of Montgomery, named McGibony; others from New Orleans, Philadelphia, Mobile, and New York. After a long investigation these parties had to give up the case as hopeless, all concluding that Maroney was an innocent man. Among the detectives, however was one from New York, Robert Boyer, by name, an old and favorite officer of Mr. Matsell when he was chief of the New York police. He had made a long and tedious examination and finding nothing definite as to what had become of the money, had turned his attention to discovering the antecedents of Maroney, but found nothing positively suspicious in his life previous to his entering the employ of the company. He discovered that Maroney was the son of a physician, and that he was born in the town of Rome, Ga.

Here I would remark that the number of titled men one meets in the South is astonishing. Every man, if he is not a doctor, a lawyer, or a clergyman, has some military title—nothing lower than captain being admissible. Of these self-imposed titles they are very jealous, and woe be to the man who neglects to address them in the proper form. Captain is the general title, and is applied indiscriminately to the captain of a steamer, or to the deck hand on his vessel.

Maroney remained in Rome until he became a young man, when he emigrated to Texas. On the breaking out of the Mexican war he joined a company of Texan Rangers, and distinguished himself in a number of battles. At the close of the war he settled in Montgomery, in the year 1851, or 1852, and was employed by Hampton & Co., owners of a line of stages, to act as their agent. On leaving this position, he was made treasurer of Johnson & May's circus, remaining with the company until it was disbanded in consequence of the pecuniary difficulties of the proprietors—caused, it was alleged, through Maroney's embezzlement of the funds, though this allegation proved false, and he remained for many years on terms of intimacy with one of the partners, a resident of Montgomery. When the company disbanded he obtained a situation as conductor on a railroad in Tennessee, and was afterwards made Assistant Superintendent, which position he resigned to take the agency of the Adams Express Company, in Montgomery. His whole life seemed spotless up to the time of the mysterious disappearance of the ten thousand dollars.

In the fall of the year, Maroney obtained leave of absence, and made a trip to the North, visiting the principal cities of the East, and also of the Northwest. He was followed on this trip, but nothing was discovered, with the single exception that his associates were not always such as were desirable in an employé, to whose keeping very heavy interests were from time to time necessarily committed. He was lost sight of at Richmond, Va., for a few days, and was supposed by the man who was following him, to have passed the time in Charleston.

The company now gave up all hope of recovering the money; but as Maroney's habits were expensive, and they had lost, somewhat, their confidence in him, they determined to remove him and place some less objectionable person in his place.

Maroney's passion for fine horses has already been alluded to. It was stated about this time that he owned several fast horses; among others, "Yankee Mary," a horse for which he was said to have paid two thousand five hundred dollars; but as he had brought seven thousand five hundred dollars with him when he entered the employ of the company, this could not be considered a suspicious circumstance.

It having been determined to remove Maroney, the Vice-President of the company wrote to the Superintendent of the Southern Division of the steps he wished taken. The Superintendent of the Southern Division visited Montgomery on the twentieth of January, 1859, but was anticipated in the matter of carrying out his instructions, by Maroney's tendering his resignation. The resignation was accepted, but the superintendent requested him to continue in charge of the office until his successor should arrive.

This he consented to do.

2023-04-15 19:43:58 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-04-15 19:43:59 INFO - Taking screenshot 2023-04-15 19:44:00 INFO - Test finished - logging out 2023-04-15 19:44:01 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:44:04 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:44:05 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:44:06 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:44:07 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:44:07 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:44:08 INFO - Button 'Log out' :: Clicking 2023-04-15 19:44:28 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Getting text from element 2023-04-15 19:44:28 INFO - Unlocking credential for current thread 2023-04-15 19:44:28 INFO - isLoggerNullAfterAnnotation-framework.utilities.Logger@3d34f997